

#### **About Me:**

Software Engineer with 10+ years of technical experience, scaling-up software products and building great teams. Interested in Senior Frontend and Fullstack Engineer roles at software product companies.

Australian Citizen with working rights in the EU. Located in Bologna, Italy from March 17.

## **Key Skills:**

- Specialised frontend experience across React, Typescript, NextJS & CSS
- 2. Strong backend commercial experience with Node, GraphQL, Express, REST, both RDBMS & NoSQL
- 3. Solution architecture on AWS: Lambda, ECS, AppSync, DynamoDB, CDK

## **Experience**

# Senior Software Engineer (Contract) MYOB

OCT 2023 - PRESENT Melbourne, AU

- Reduced inbound calls to support phone lines with the introduction of Support Article Search with Algolia. Built with reuse in mind, we used the same component on other areas of the website.
- Strategic guidance on architecture decisions around NextJS, localisation and partial prerendering.
- Other areas of focus: core web vitals improvements; integration with headless CMS Contentful; middleware performance improvements; and a website rebrand.

## Senior Software Engineer

Stax (by Versent)

OCT 2018 - OCT 2023

Melbourne, AU 📍

Stax is a B2B SaaS cloud management platform, for deploying and monitoring AWS infrastructure. In October 2023, Stax & Versent sold to Telstra for \$267.5m.

- Ownership of long-term strategy for a production frontend application, a component library, style system and a backend API service.
- Led architecture and build for a backend-for-frontend project. This simplied interfacing with microservices as the business grew, leveraging highly scalable event-driven, serverless architecture.
- Scaled-up engineering capabilities from 5 engineers to 30+, establishing best practices and processes for our growing organisation.
- Mentored and supported junior engineers, helping them grow their skills and confidence through pair programming, code reviews and leading workshops.
- Set-up best-practice foundations for our React app with unit testing, end-to-end tests, linting, CI processes and docs.
- Increased consistency across multiple frontend projects and across Engineering and Design teams, with a style system and component library implementation.
- Tech: Typescript, React, GraphQL, Apollo, Jest, Playwright, NodeJS, AWS Lambda, AppSync, DynamoDB Serverless, SQS, SAM, CDK and more.

### **Frontend Engineer (Contract)**

Bureau of Meteorology

MAR 2018 - OCT 2018 Melbourne, AU

- Building a new weather experience for the general public in Australia's top 30 most visited websites
- Improved reliability and protyping speed with static typing & tree-structured state management library (Typescript, Mobx and mobx-state-tree; integrations with weather API services)

**Frontend Developer** 

Belong (by Telstra)

NOV 2016 - MAR 2018 Melbourne, AU

Graduate » Consultant (Frontend Developer)
Deloitte Digital

JAN 2014 - NOV 2016 Melbourne, AU

## Education

### Bachelor of Business (Information Systems) 2012-2015